dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Formation of Team Minato
ふざけるな あの野郎！
I wish he'd stop messing around!
あんなヤツと
一緒にやってられるかよ！
Who wants to be together with him?!
そう怒るな。
カカシはもう 班を離れるんだから。
Don't be so upset.
Kakashi is already leaving the team.
けどよ…。
Still...
(オビト)あの すみません。
Um, excuse me.
カカシって はたけカカシのことですか？
By "Kakashi," are you talking
about Kakashi Hatake?
は？
誰だ？ お前。
Who are you?
俺 アカデミーで
カカシと一緒だったんです。
Kakashi and I were at
the Academy together.
へぇ… じゃあ友達か？
Oh, so you're friends?
あ いえ… 友達ってほどじゃ。
No, I wouldn't call us "friends."
やなヤツだろう？
え？
He's pretty nasty, right?
あんなヤツと一緒じゃ
任務なんてできねえよ。
We can't complete a mission
with a guy like that.
任務…。
Mission?
《そっか。
カカシはもう 任務に出てるのか…》
Oh, right... Kakashi is already
going on missions.
何かあったんですか？
Did something happen?
あの野郎 仲間がケガしたって→
That guy always prioritizes
the mission over everything.
敵の中に取り残されたって→
Even if his teammate is hurt,
or is left behind in enemy territory.
お構いなしに
任務を優先させやがる。
あれじゃ
仲間なんて やってられねえよ。
There's no way
we can work with him.
お前も アイツと組むことになったら
気をつけるんだな。
If you ever have to
team up with him, be careful.
《任務を… 優先？》
Prioritizes... the mission?
((カカシ : 仲間は絶対に助ける。
それが俺の流儀だ))
I'll save my friends,
no matter what.
That's my Ninja Way.
《アイツが…。
Him? He'd do that?
そんな…》
なぁ リン。 最近 カカシに会った？
Say, Rin...
Do you see Kakashi these days?
(リン)ううん。 街で
ちょっと見かけるくらいかな。
No, I only catch glimpses
of him in town.
ずっと任務で
里の外に出てるみたいだし。
I think he's away on missions
most of the time.
ふ～ん…。
どうして？
Why?
昨日 カカシの噂を聞いたんだ。
I heard some rumors
about Kakashi yesterday.
あんまりいい噂じゃなかったけど。
They weren't good rumors.
前に見かけたときには
ずいぶん雰囲気が変わってたし。
Last time I saw him,
he seemed to have changed a lot too.
もしかしたら お父さんのことが
関係してるのかも…。
Could it be something to do
with his father?
何か知ってるのか？
Do you know something?
ううん。
Well, no...
そっか…。
Oh, I see.
じゃあね オビト。
Okay, Obito. See you tomorrow!
また明日。
おう。
Yeah.
カカシ…。
Kakashi...
よう カカシ！ 元気にしてんのか？
Hey, Kakashi!
How's it going?
いろいろ評判は聞いてるぜ。
I've been hearing a lot about you.
活躍してるみたいだな。
Looks like you've been
seeing a lot of action.
何かあったのか？ 心配事なら…。
Hey, did something happen?
If something's on your mind...
お前に心配してもらうほど
落ちぶれちゃいない。
I'm not so desperate that
I need you to worry about me.
お前…。
Hey... you...
俺にかまうな。
Leave me alone.
カカシ…。
Kakashi...
見つけた オビト！
I found you, Obito!
ん？ リン！
Rin!
うわっ！
あっ！
大丈夫？
Are you all right?!
ハハハッ… ちょっと滑っちまった。
I just slipped.
大丈夫 大丈夫。
I'm okay. I'm okay.
こんな雨なのに 修業してたんだ。
You're training in this rain?
あぁ。 アイツに追いつくには→
Yeah... I figured I have to try harder
if I'm going to catch up to that guy.
もっと努力しねえとって思って。
アイツ？
カカシだよ。
"That guy"?
I mean, Kakashi.
いつか ギャフンと言わせたいんだ。
One day, I'll surprise him.
じゃなくちゃ 火影になんて
なれるわけねえし…。
Otherwise, I can't become
the Hokage.
それに アイツは もう
任務だってこなしてる。
Besides, he's already going
on missions.
だから もっと努力しねえと→
I have to work harder or the gap
between us will get bigger!
どんどん離されてっちまうからさ。
その意気よ。 頑張れ オビト！
That's the spirit!
Go for it, Obito!
あぁ！
Yeah!
(ミナト)失礼します。
Excuse me.
(ミナト)お呼びですか？
You wanted to see me?
お前に頼みたいことがある。
I want to ask you a favor.
はたけカカシは優秀な忍だ。
Kakashi Hatake is
an extremely talented shinobi.
しかし ルールに厳密なあまり
配属された どの班でも→
However, he fusses too much
about sticking to the rules
先輩や同僚とぶつかり
問題を起こす。
and clashes with his superiors
and teammates.
いかに 技が優れていようが→
He may excel in technique,
but as a human, he has much to learn.
人間としては まだまだ未熟だ。
ルールを破り 仲間を守ったため→
His father broke the rules
to protect his comrades,
自ら命を絶った 父親の死が
影を落としているのだろう。
and then took his own life...
His death has cast
a shadow over Kakashi.
それで 私に預かれと。
And you want to place him
under my supervision...
やばい やばい やばい！
Oh no, oh no!
GRADUATION CEREMONY
はっ…。
うわっ！
信じられない！
I can't believe you were late
入学式にも 卒業式にも
遅れてくるなんて…。
for both your entrance and
graduation ceremonies!
もう終わっちゃったよ 卒業式。
Graduation is over!
だって おばあちゃんがよぉ…。
But there was this old lady...
オビト おばあちゃんの
遭遇確率 高くない？
You have an awfully high rate
of encounters with old people, don't you?
まあ なんか
最近 待ち伏せされてるからな。
Lately... I've been getting ambushed
by a lot of them.
(リン)もう それ 確信犯じゃない！
That sounds premeditated!
もう…。
Really...
ほら！ こっち来て。
Come on...
This way!
(リン)卒業証書 うちはオビト。
Here is the graduation certificate
for Obito Uchiha!
木ノ葉隠れ忍者アカデミーの
卒業を証する。
"This certifies that
you have graduated
"from the Hidden Leaf Ninja Academy.
それと 雨の日も 風の日も→
"You are commended
for persevering
よく ここまで
修業と 努力を続けました。
"through the rain and wind
to reach this milestone!"
はい！ 卒業おめでとう！
Here! Congratulations!
リン…。
Rin...
ありがとう リン。
Thank you, Rin.
みんな いねえけど→
No one's here to watch...
火影のじいちゃんに渡されるより
ずっと嬉しいや。
But this makes me happier than
receiving it from that old-man Hokage!
これで 私たちは
下忍なんだから シャンとしてよ。
We're genin now,
so you have shape up.
ああ わかってる。
あっ そういえば→
Yeah, I know.
We'll now be part of a 3-man squad
and go on missions, right?
下忍になったら
スリーマンセルで任務につくんだろ？
その組み分けって
もう発表されたの？
Have the teams already
been announced?
ええ されたわよ。
Yes, they have.
それで 俺とリンは？
So, are you and me...
それが…。
Well...
まさか… 別？
Don't tell me...
we're on different...
残念ながら 一緒の班よ。
ウソッ！
Unfortunately,
we're on the same team!
No way!
ホント！ また オビトの面倒みる
羽目になるなんて…。
Yup. I'm stuck looking
after you again...
《やった！ やった！》
Yes! Yes!
あっ！
それで もう一人は？
And who's the third member?
それがね…。
About that...
遅いぞ オビト。
やっと来たね。
You're late, Obito!
You're finally here.
You must be Obito.
キミがオビトか。
待ってたよ。
We've been waiting for you.
ハァ… ギリか。
Barely made it...
大遅刻だよ。
You're really late.
今日から
キミの上司になるミナトだ よろしく。
I'm Minato, your leader from today.
Glad to meet you.
おう！
Yeah!
ともかく
４人で最初の演習をやるよ。
Anyway, let's have
our first training session together.
は はい！
R-Right!
この演習は キミたちの
チームワークを見るためだ。
In this session,
I want to see your teamwork.
チームワーク？
Teamwork?
やってもらうのは これ。
And the exercise will be... this.
ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
ハァーッ！
みんな合格だ。
You all pass!
では 明日から
早速 任務についてもらう。
All right...
We'll start our first mission tomorrow.
よっしゃ！ 実戦で
俺の実力 見せてやるぜ！
That's more like it!
I'll show what I've got
in a real battle!
とは言っても 最初は
里の中の任務だけどね。
Actually, this first mission
is inside the village.
ペット探しとか
落とし物をみつけるとか。
Like finding a lost pet
or a lost item.
うぅ… それって雑用じゃん。
Those are just odd jobs!
雑用でも 任務は任務だよ。
A mission is a mission.
それを ちゃんとこなせたら
もっと重要な任務につけるよ。
If you succeed, then I'll assign
more important missions.
カカシは
もう何度も実戦に出てるから→
Kakashi, you've been on
many missions already
今更 そんな任務は
不満かもしれないけど→
and this may seem boring,
しっかりやってね。
but do your best anyway.
よし！ カカシ 勝負だ！
はぁ？
Okay! Kakashi, I challenge you!
明日からの任務
どっちが多くこなせるか。
Let's see who can
complete more missions.
くだらん。 勝手にやれ。
That's stupid. Do as you please.
逃げるのか？
なに!?
You chicken?
What did you say?
いない。
It's not here.
いないな…。
いた？
いない。
Found it?
No.
It's not here either.
こっちもいない。
案外 ペット探しって大変。
Looking for a lost pet
isn't easy, is it?
だが
この程度の任務もこなせなきゃ→
But if we can't succeed
at something like this,
いつまで経っても 俺たちは
本当の任務に出してもらえない。
our team will never be sent
on real missions.
そういえば オビトはどこだ？
By the way, where's Obito?
全部 １人で解決するって
張り切って→
He was determined to
do everything alone,
どっか行っちゃったけど…。
and went off somewhere.
本当に
俺に勝てるつもりでいるのか？
Is he serious about beating me?
やぁ オビトちゃん！
Oh, Obito...
その猫なら この先の屋根で
ひなたぼっこしてたよ。
That cat was on the rooftop
up ahead basking in the sun.
オビトちゃん それなら
公園のベンチに置いてあったよ。
Obito, I saw that thing
on a park bench.
そうそう
いい お茶菓子もらったから→
Oh right, by the way,
I have some yummy sweets
you can take with you.
お土産にあげるよ！
ニャーン。
ヘヘヘ 猫探しに 落とし物探し→
Finding a lost pet, and a lost item!
ばあちゃんたちが
協力してくれて→
Solved them both,
thanks to the grannies.
片づいちった！
それに お土産も。
And I even got treats!
すごい オビトのおばあちゃん人気！
You're so popular
with the old ladies, Obito.
伊達に毎日 遅刻してるわけじゃ
なかったのね。
You really weren't lying
all those times were you late.
情けは人のためならず。
"One good deed deserves another."
今回は オビトの日々の行動が
役に立ったんだね。
This time, Obito's kindness
was returned.
どうだ カカシ！
How's that, Kakashi?!
ふむ… たった一日で→
All the odd jobs in the village
were taken care of in one day.
里の雑用依頼が
全部 消えてしまったわい。
(オビト)だろ!? 俺は
火影になる男だからよ！
Right? It's because I'm the man
who will become the Hokage!
この程度は当然だぜ！
This is nothing!
(ミナト)火影様 どうやら彼らは→
Lord Hokage, I believe this team
is far more skilled than we thought.
我々が思ったより
はるかに優秀なようです。
そうじゃの。
You're right. Kakashi already
has lots of field experience.
カカシは実戦の任務経験も豊富だし→
明日からの お前の任務に
同行させてみるか。
Perhaps I shall send them along
with you on your mission tomorrow.
ミナト先生の任務？
On Minato Sensei's mission?!
Is this a real mission?!
それって ホントの実戦か!?
そうじゃ。
ミナト指名の任務が入っておる。
Yes. And the client specifically
requested Minato.
任務といっても Ｃランクだよ。
It's a C-rank mission.
Although the risk is low,
危険が まったくないと言ったら
ウソだけど かなり低い。
I'd be lying if I said
there's absolutely none.
ミナトの任務の間→
I was planning to assign you
to more odd jobs in the village
お前たちには 里の残りの雑用を
頼もうかと思っておったが→
while Minato was away.
その雑用がなくなってはのう。
But there are no more requests.
かといって
遊ばせておくわけにもいかんしな。
And, I can't let you just
wait around.
よっしゃ～！
これで私たちも→
Yes!
This means we're going
on our first real mission.
本格的に任務開始ね！
じゃあ みんな
明日から頼んだよ！
Okay then...
I'm counting on you all from tomorrow.
(３人)はい！
– Yes, sir!
Well, Kakashi?!
(オビト)どうだ？ カカシ。
You should be grateful to me.
少しは俺に感謝しろよ。
俺のおかげで
雑用から解放されたんだからな。
I'm the only reason why
there are no more odd jobs to do.
カカシ オビトのこと怒らないでね。
Kakashi, don't get upset with Obito.
オビトは ずっと
カカシのこと気にしてたんだよ。
Obito's been worried about you
for a long time.
カカシが変わった気がするって…。
He thinks you've changed...
W-What're you saying, Rin?!
な… 何 言いだすんだよ リン！
だって 本当のことでしょう？
Well, it's true.
And you always said that
Kakashi was better than you...
それに カカシは
いつでも俺の前を行ってる。
だから それに追いつくんだって
ずっと１人で修業してたじゃない。
So you trained hard to catch up!
い… 言ってねえし!!
してねえし！ 気のせいだし!!
Did not! I never said that!
You're imagining things!
はい 仲直りの握手。
みんな同じチームなんだから。
Come on, let's all shake hands.
We're on the same team now.
誰が コイツと握手なんて…。
I'm not shaking hands with this guy!
もう… しようがないわね。
Really...
You're both hopeless!
じゃ 私が２人をつなぐわ。
Then...
I'll connect the both of you.
Okay guys, for this mission,
((ミナト : いいかい？
今回の任務は他里の忍の護衛だ。
we will be escorting shinobi
from another village.
その１人が 密書を持っている。
One of them is carrying
a secret missive.
つまり それを守るわけだね。
Namely, that's what we are guarding.
CONFIDENTIAL
There will also be three other escorts
from the requesting village.
依頼の里からも３人の護衛がつく。
If fighting breaks out...
万が一 戦闘になったら→
First and foremost, I want you three
to make sure you're safe.
キミたちは 第一に
身の安全をはかってほしい。
Understood?
(わかったね？))
All right!
よ～し！ この任務で大活躍して
一気に火影になってやるぜ！
I'm gonna show my stuff big-time
and make it to Hokage!
It's not going to be that easy.
そんな簡単に
なれるわけないでしょ。
Obito, were you even listening
to Minato Sensei?
オビト お前は ミナト先生の話を
聞いてなかったのか？
俺たちのバトルは なしだ。
We are not to engage in
any kind of battle.
Besides, we'd only get
in Minato Sensei's way.
それに ミナト先生がいるのに
俺たちが戦っても足手まといだ。
Is he really that amazing?
あの先生 そんなすげぇのか？
Haven't you ever heard of
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf?
木ノ葉の黄色い閃光を
知らないのか？
I have.
私 聞いたことがあるわ。
He's an incredible shinobi whose fame
has spread to other villages too.
他の里にも名がとどろいてる
すごい忍だって。
(カカシ)波風ミナト
次期火影と噂される人だ。
And he's our teacher,
Minato Namikaze,
the man touted to become
the next Hokage.
マジ!? 俺たち そんな
すげぇ人に教わってるの？
Seriously?! Someone that great
is teaching us?
I feel my blood rushing!
なんか やる気 出てきたぜ!!
Man, I wish someone
would attack us.
ああ…
早く 敵 襲ってこねえかな。
Jeez...
ったく…。
Hey, I wonder who's stronger,
なぁ 木ノ葉の黄色い閃光と
木ノ葉の白い牙。
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf
or the White Fang of the Leaf?
どっちが強いのかな？
えっ？
オ… オビト。
O-Obito!
木ノ葉の里には 白い牙って
呼ばれた英雄がいたらしいぜ。
The Hidden Leaf had a hero
named the White Fang.
里を守って
殉職しちまったらしいけど…。
But I heard he died
protecting the village.
知らないのか？
Haven't you heard of him?
No, I haven't.
知らん。
ん… カカシ？
Kakashi?
何だ アイツ。
What's with him?
《ん… どうも様子がおかしいね。
This is strange.
囲まれている。 しかも相当な数。
どういうことだ？
We're surrounded...
There are quite a few of them.
What's going on?
This is far more dangerous than
the rank assigned to this mission.
任務ランクとは明らかに違う危険度。
I have to stop them here
before I'm completely surrounded.
ここで食い止めなければ
更に囲まれる。
彼らを連れてきたのは
まずかったな。
Bringing along the team
might have been a mistake.
頼りになるのは…
彼なら１人は守れる。
Who can I depend on?
He can guard one person.
I'll have to guard the other one.
あと１人は 俺が守るしかないか》
Everyone, listen up.
(ミナト)みんな聞いてくれ。
What is it, Sensei?
(オビト)何だよ 先生。
Looks like the enemy is on our tail.
どうやら後方から敵が迫っている。
マジ!? やるの？
Seriously?! We're gonna fight?!
Obito! This is not a game!
オビト これは遊びじゃない。
Uh, yes sir...
あ はい…。
かなりの数がいる。
There are quite a few of them.
Obito and I will track back
to confront them.
俺とオビトは ここから戻って
追っ手を撃退する。
In the meantime, Kakashi
and Rin will complete the mission.
カカシとリンの２人は
その間に任務を果たせ。
お前たちが逃げのびるのが
最優先だ！
It's imperative that you two escape.
– Yes, sir!
(２人)はい！
All right... Let's go, Obito!
じゃあ いくよ オビト！
ラジャ！
Roger!
Oh man, Minato Sensei!
なんだよ ミナト先生。
カカシじゃなくて俺を選ぶなんて。
To have you pick me
instead of Kakashi...
ヘヘッ 結局 俺のことを→
This just means you depend on me!
頼りにしてるってことじゃねえか。
Obito, we're going to lure
the enemy without a fight
オビト バトルはせずに
囮になるつもりで→
and separate them
from the main group.
敵を本隊から引き離すんだ。
I know that!
わかってるって！
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
Oh, not bad.
おっ やるね。
I wasn't kidding about
practicing every day!
毎日の修業は伊達じゃないぜ。
I'll take down
every single one of them!
俺が全員ぶっ倒してやる！
Don't get carried away!
I said no fighting!
調子に乗らない！ バトルはせずに…。
あっ！
Obito!
オビト！
You're in the way!
邪魔だ！
《強ぇ》
He's strong!
You're just a kid!
ガキが！
その程度で俺に勝てるつもりか！
You can't beat me with that!
Damn it!
《クソッ こんなところで
負けてたまるかよ》
I'm not going to lose here!
俺は！
I'm...
火影になる男だ！
... gonna become the Hokage!
うわっ！
I did it!
《やった》
あ… 影分身。
A shadow clone?!
You're mine!
もらった！
Not good!
やべえ…。
うわっ…。
Are you all right?
大丈夫かい？
Minato Sensei!
ミナト先生。
This is not good...
《これは まずいね…》
They're here.
きたか… リン 先行しろ。
わかった。
Rin! Go on ahead!
Got it.
Damn—!
しまっ…。
うっ…。
あ～っ！
あっ！ カカシ 助けないと。
Kakashi! We have to save him!
Minato Sensei is still
nearby right now!
今ならまだ ミナト先生のところへ
すぐに戻って知らせれば…。
If we turn back and let him know...
No! A shinobi's duty is to
carry out his mission!
ダメだ。 任務の遂行が忍の掟だ。
Kakashi...
カカシ。
走れ 逃げるのを優先しろ。
Run! Getting away is imperative!
Once we're in the forest,
the village will be near!
森を抜ければ里は近い。
They won't pursue us that far!
そこまで行けば
ヤツらは追ってこないはずだ。
Understood!
わかった。
We've come this far.
We should be safe.
ここまで来れば 大丈夫だろう。
オビトは？
先生がついてる。
What about Obito?
Sensei is with him.
I'm sure they're fine.
きっと無事だ。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
さすが 黄色い閃光の部隊だ。
I must hand it to
the Yellow Flash's team.
Thanks to you, the secret missive
will be delivered safely.
キミたちのおかげで
無事に密書は 届けられる。
いえ 残念ながら
１人の犠牲者が出ましたが…。
Don't mention it.
Unfortunately, one man had
to be sacrificed.
That could not be helped.
それは しかたがないことだ。
However... he won't be...
だが…。
犠牲者は→
the only sacrifice!
それだけじゃ済まないがな！
うわっ！
What the—?!
なに！
どういうこと？
What's going on?
S-So you're... the traitors!
お お前らが 裏切り者か…。
お前たちが任務の遂行に
こだわってくれたおかげで→
Since you were just so focused
on completing the mission,
you made our mission easy.
こっちの任務も
やりやすくなった。
Even someone like the Yellow Flash
can't span this distance quickly.
黄色い閃光も
これだけ離れればすぐには来ない。
Sorry, but you're going
to have to die too.
悪いが
お前たちもここで死んでもらう！
No way...
くっ…。
そんな…。
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
Kakashi, you didn't...
You didn't leave someone
to die, did you?
＜夜の港に
影が浮かぶ。
I only prioritized the mission.
I followed the rules.
潮の香りに紛れて消えた
あの人の影＞
But the result of doing that,
is all this!
Stop, Obito.
What happened is something
that could not be foreseen.
It's not Kakashi's fault.
Damn it. I'm going.
Where are you going?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"You'll Be My Backup"
＜群れにはぐれた海鳥が
かすれた声で鳴いている。
Isn't it obvious?! I'm going
to go save those guys!